Guide to the Benoit Mandelbrot Papers M1857
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 8. Research Articles and Other Writings
  - DLA (diffustion limited aggregates) - correspondence with Amnon Ahrony and Yevgeny Vilensky, article drafts, notes, figures, 2000-2001 (Box 110, Folders 8-9)
  - DLA (diffustion limited aggregates) - correspondence with Amnon Ahrony and Yevgeny Vilensky, article drafts, notes, figures, 2000-2001 (Box 111, Folders 1-2)
  - Documents on fractals/multifractals in finance, since 1962 (heavily edited drafts) (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Each fractal set has a unique fractal dimension (edited handwrittne/computer printout drafts), 1983 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Econophysics in the mid-twentieth century, 2006 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - Efficient artibraging, and the random walk an Martingale models of price variation (edited computer printout drafts), 1969 Dec 28 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Electric current through fractal lattices I: Quasi-linear lattices and related fractal measure, J. A. Given and BBM, 1983 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Electric current through quasi-linear fractal lattices, J. A. Given and BBM (edited computer printout drafts), 1983 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Encyclopedia of Statistical Sciences - entries by BBM, circa 1985 (Box 332, Folder 9)
  - Enrico Fermi's model for the law of Pareto (drafts) (Box 219, Folder 8)
  - Ensembles de Julia de Fatou et de Mandelbrot, 1989 (edited drafts) (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Exactly self-similar left-sided multifractal measures, BBM, C. J. G. Evertsz, Y. Hayakawa, 1990 (edited printouts, figures) (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Examples of multinomial multifractal measures that have negative latent values for the dimension f(a) - Fractals, proceedings of the ERICE meeting 1988, 1988-1989 (edited computer printouts) (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - The expected value of a price, tomorrow, and the future distribution of the speculator's wealth (clean typescript; photocopy) (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - The eye in mathematical thinking: A historical and personal perspective (rough handwritten/computer printout draft) (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Facettes fractales de l'anatomie - La Recherche, 1977 (Box 219, Folder 9)
  - A family of left-sided multiplicative multifractals, and DLA, 1989-1990 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Family roots of a Maverick (edited draft) (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - Fast fractional Gaussian noises (final typescript) (Box 219, Folder 10)
  - Fast Fractional Gaussian Noises (edited computer printout draft) (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Fatal attractors, 1981 Jan 22 (edited drafts) (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Firm size distribution "laws" and industrial concentration, revised 1966 (edited drafts) (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Foreword and the story of the conditional cosmological principle, 2001 (handwritten/computer printout drafts, heavily edited) (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Foreword to Applied Mathematics by Herbert W. Franke, 1979 (Box 219, Folder 11)
  - Foreword to Discovery of Cosmic Fractals by Y. Baryshev and P. Teerikorpi, 2001 (edited draft; email to authors) (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Foreword to Fractals by Heinz-Otto Peitgen Fractals and the rebirth of experimental mathematics, 1990 (edited computer printouts) (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Foreword to Long Range Dependent Stochastic Processes: Theory and Applications, Springer-Verlag, 2003 (edited drafts) (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Foreword to the first issue of the periodical Fractals: An Interdisciplinary Journal on the Complex Geometry of Nature, 1992 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - Formes nouvelles du hasard dans les sciences (second draft, heavily edited), 1973 Jan 15 (Box 219, Folder 12)
  - Fractal art for the sake of science, circa 1984 (handwritten draft) (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Fractal aspects of materials: An introduction, circa 1980s (edited computer printouts) (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - The fractal character of fracture surfaces of metals (edited computer printout drafts), 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Fractal Measures (their infinite moment sequences and dimensions) and multiplicative chaos: early works and open problems (edited drafts) (Box 219, Folder 13)
  - Fractional Brownian motion and sums of microplanes, R. Cioczek-George and BBM, 1994 Apr (edited computer printouts) (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - A fractal can be a set, a measure or a graph (heavily edited computer printout) (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - The fractal character of fracture surfaces of metals to appear in Nature as a letter to the editor in early 1984 (edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - Fractal curves and surfaces: The midpoint displacement technique and its application to model reliefs, circa 1980s (handwritten draft; heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - Fractional dimension and stellar distribution, circa 1971 (typescript) (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - The fractal geometry of chaos and of plain mess, 1989-1992 (clean and edited computer printouts) (Box 112, Folder 15)
  - Fractal geometry: What is it, and what does it do? circa 1988 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Fractal lacunarity and scenarios for the near-isotropipc distributions of galaxies, 1998 (edited computer printout) (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Fractal lacunarity I: An illustrated statement of the problem (heavily edited hadwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Fractal lacunarity II: A measure based on correlation as applied to scaling Trema sets (handwritten/typescript drafts) (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Fractal lacunarity IV: A measure based on the shell prefactor as applied to Cantor sets and the like (clean draft) (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Fractal mountains and dragons, with an excursion through fractal music, 1987 (edited computer printout) (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Fractal properties of rain, and a fractal model, S. Lovejoy and BBM, circa 1980s (handwritten/computer printout drafts, edited) (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Fractal properties of rain, and a fractal model, by S. Lovejoy and BBM (edited computer printout) (Box 219, Folder 14)
  - Fractal squig models of percolation clusters, and related squigs (edited computer printout draft), 1983 Apr 22 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Fractal sums of pulses and a challenge to the distinction between local and global dependence (heavily edited drafts) (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - Fractal sums of pulses challenge the distinction between local and global dependence (heavily edited drafts) (Box 113, Folder 9)
  - Fractal sums of pulses (FSP) and new random variables and functions, 1984 (edited computer printouts) (Box 113, Folder 10)
  - Fractal sums of pulses (FSP) and new random variables and functions (edited drafts), 1984 Jul 5 (Box 219, Folder 15)
  - Fractal sums of pulses: second differences, by BBM and Michael Frame (clena draft) (Box 219, Folder 16)
  - Fractal sums of pulses: Self-affine global dependence and lateral limit theorems, circa 1994 (heavily edited drafts) (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Fractal sums of pulses: Self-affine global mesodiffusion and lateral limit theorems (clean and edited drafts) (Box 219, Folder 17)
  - Les fractales: Objets mathematiques, models physiques et creations artistiques (edited typescript/computer printout drafts), 1983 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Les fractales: Objets mathematiques, modeles physiques et creations artistiques (edited computer printout drafts), 1983-1984 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Les fractals et l'art algorithmique (heavily edited printouts) (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Fractals - entry by BBM for the Encyclopedia of Physical Science and Technology (heavily edited drafts) (Box 219, Folder 22)
  - Fractals: A Geometry of Nature (edited drafts), 1990 (Box 302, Folder 9)
  - Fractals and a form of art for the sake of science, 1989 (edited drafts) (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Fractals, and a form of art for the sake of science (Box 219, Folder 18)
  - Fractals and a practical approach to randomness, 2006 (edited drafts; correspondence with Nassim Nicholas Taleb) (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Fractals and fractal dimensions - prepared for the Encyclopedia of Physical Science and Technology, circa 1986 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 114, Folders 5-6)
  - Fractals and some of the statistics problems that they raise, 1989 (heavily edited draft) (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - Fractals and the study of economic jumps and swings (computer printout draft) (Box 219, Folder 19)
  - Fractals' contribution to visual mathematics (edited draft) (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Fractals - Fruit of a wandering mind (edited computer printouts) (Box 219, Folder 20)
  - Fractals: How to imitate the mountains, the clouds and the trees, and to create wild and wonderful new shapes, circa 1986 (edited computer printouts) (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Fractals in physics: Squig clusters, diffusions, and the unicity of fractal dimensionality - presented at 15th IUPAP International Conference on Thermodynamics and Statistical Physics, Edinburgh, 1983 Nov 10 (edited draft) (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Fractals in physics: Squig clusters, diffusions and other short topics, old or new (edited handwritten/computer printout drafts), 1983 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Fractals in physics (continued): Squig clusters, diffusions, fractal measures, and the unicity of fractal dimensionality (edited handwritten/computer printout drafts), 1983 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Fractals keeping the rough edges (clean computer printout), 1996 Jun 19 (Box 219, Folder 21)
  - A fractal's lacunarity, and how it can be tuned and measured (handwritten/computer printout drafts, edited) (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Fractals: Mathematical land of enchantment (edited computer printout drafts), 1983 Jun 23 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Fractals, the computer and mathematics education International Congress of Mathematics Education ICME-7, Quebec City, Canada, 1992 (heavily edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Fractals, their transfer matrices and their Eigen-dimensional sequences, BBM, Y. Gefen, A. Ahrony, J. Peyrie, circa 1980s (edited computer printouts) (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Fractional Brownian motion, self-similar processes, and applications, BBM and John W. Van Ness, Technical Report No. 15, 1966 Mar 1 (multiple drafts, handwritten/computer printout drafts, edited) (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Fractional dimension in cosmography (typescript) (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - From the monsters of Cantor and Peano to the fractal geometry of nature (Box 219, Folder 23)
  - General and left-sided multifractals, 1989 (heavily edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Geometric facets of statistical physics: Scaling and fractals, circa 1970s-1980s (edited computer printouts) (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - A geometry able to include mountains and clouds - chapter in unknown book, 2004 Apr 5 (clean galley) (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - The geometry of chaos and of plain mess, and fractals, 1989 (heavily edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - Geometry of planar ising clusters: Gap independence and global structure, BBM, Romualdo Paster-Satorras, Erik M. Rauch, 1996 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 115, Folder 10)
  - The geometry of turbulence I: Fractically homogenous intermittent dissipation, 1974 (clean computer printouts/photocopies) (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - The geometry of turbulence I: Fractally homogenous intermittent dissipation, revised 1974 (typescript, photocopies, edited) (Box 116, Folders 1-2)
  - The grey and the green: A foreword (heavily edited handwritten/typescript drafts) (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Growth with unchanged fractal dimension but decreasing inhomogenity, BBM, C. J. G. Evertsz, L. Woog, 1992-1995 (clean and edited drafts) (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Handbook on heavy tails in finance edited by Prof. (heavily edited drafts) (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - The harmonic measure on diffusion limited aggregates: New scaling rules and a departure from self-similarity, BBM, C. J. G. Evertsz, 1990 Jul 23 (edited printout) (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - The Hausdorff dimension of certain self-affine fractals, and its implications, circa 1980s (handwritten/edited computer printout drafts) (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - The Hausdorff dimension of certain self-affine fractals (edited drafts) (Box 220, Folder 2)
  - Heavy tails in finance for independent or multifractal price increments - chapter in Handbook on Heavy Tails in Finance edited by Svetlozar T. Rachev (heavily edited drafts) (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Heavy tails in finance for independent or multifractal price increments 2002 May 9 (edited draft) (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Hierarchic clustering of galaxies in two fractal models, circa 1970s-1980s (edited drafts) (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Hierarchic clustering of galaxies in two fractal models (edited handwritten/computer printout drafts), 1982 Aug 17 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - High fidelity graphic models as evidence in scientific research, 1979 (edited draft) (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - How long is the coast of Britain? Statistical self-similarity and fractional dimension (edited computer printouts) (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - How the finance gurus get risk all wrong, by BBM and N. N. Taleb - Fortune Magazine, 2005 Jul 11 (Box 220, Folder 3)
  - How to explain and discover the eye in science and the Greek myth of Antaeus (clean draft), 2005 (Box 220, Folder 4)
  - Hydrology using self-affine processes, BBM and J. R. Wallis (edited computer printout) (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Les images fractales. Un art pour l'amour de la science, et ses applications pratiques, circa 1980s (edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 117, Folder 14)
  - Les images fractales. Un art pour l'amour de la science, et ses applications pratiques (edited computer printout draft), 1984 Jan 27 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - The inescapable need for fractal tools in finance, 2004 (clean computer printouts) (Box 117, Folder 15)
  - The inexhaustible function z squared minus m (edited draft) (Box 117, Folder 16)
  - Informal introduction to the infinite variance syndrome (edited photocopy) (Box 117, Folder 17)
  - Informal introduction to the infinite variance syndrome (edited photocopy) (Box 117)
  - Intergalactic voids and filaments, and why they necessarily occur in fractal models, 1983 (clean printout) (Box 117, Folder 18)
  - Intergalactic voids and filaments, and why they necessarily occur in fractal models (heavily edited handwritten/computer printout drafts), 1983 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Intermittent turbulence - Symposium on Turbulence of Fluids and Plasmas, 1968 Apr 16-18 (photocopy) (Box 117, Folder 19)
  - Intermittent turbulence and self similar cascades I: Introduction to properties other than spectral (photocopy) (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Intermittent turbulence and self similar cascades: Divergence of high moments and dimension of the carrier, circa 1970s (annotated photocopies; clean typescript) (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - The intensity of persistence in non periodic cycles: An application of R/S analysis in economics (edited typescript) (Box 220, Folder 5)
  - An instrument in which errors followed the Cauchy distribution (edited photocopy), 1963 Apr 1 (Box 219, Folder 1)
  - Interrelations between scaling histogram tails and scaling dependence in financial prices (handwritten/computer printout drafts, heavily edited) (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - An introduction to multifractal distribution functions (edited and clean computer printouts) (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Introduction to multifractal products of independent random functions - Random multiplicative multifractal measures, part 1, J. Barral and BBM (heavily edited compute printout) (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Invariant multifractal measures in chaotic Hamiltonian systems, and related structures, 1987 (edited computer printouts) (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Is there persistence in stock price movements? circa 1960s (edited photocopy) (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Lacunarity as a source of sampling variability for estimates of fractal dimension of self-similar fractals, circa 1980s (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Lacunarity: A source of sampling variability for estimates of fractal dimension of self-similar fractals (heavily edited draft) (Box 220, Folder 6)
  - A lecture on fractals delivered in 1990 - Nobel Conference (heavily edited drafts) (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Lewis Fry Richardson and prematurity in science, circa 1989 (heavily edited partial drafts) (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Limit logonormal multifractal measures - Frontiers of Physics and Landau Memorial Conference - Proceedings of the 1988 Tel Aviv Meeting, 1988-1989 (edited computer printouts) (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Limit theorems on the self normalized range for weakly and strongly dependent processes (edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Linguistique statistique macroscopique - Theorie mathematique de la loi de Zipf, 1957 Jun 13 (Box 220, Folder 7)
  - Lognormal distribution, Paretian approximation and the behavior of the sample moments, circa 1960s (clean and edited photocopies) (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Long run linearity, locally Gaussian processes, H-spectra and infinite variances, 1966 (edited typescript and photocopies) (Box 118, Folders 4-5)
  - Long run linearity, locally Gaussian processes, H-spectra and infinite variances, 1966 (clean typescript) (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Low growth probabilities in diffusion limited aggregates (DLA), 1990 (edited computer printouts) (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Macroscopic statistical laws of behavior (edited computer printout) (Box 220, Folder 8)
  - Macro-statistical models and aggregative laws of behavior (clean partial drafts) (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Mass fractal lacunarity, Levy dusts, Mittag-Leffler statistics, and perceived dimension, Raphael Blumenfeld and BBM, 1996 (edited printouts) (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Mass prefactor and residual lacunarity for Cantor, Koch, Levy and other fractal sets (heavily edited drafts) (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - The mathematical theory of self-similar chance phenomena: An introduction and a bibliography from 1964 Oslo lecture (manuscript/typescript drafts) (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Mathematics, art, and the story of the invincible Antaeus (clean computer printout) (Box 220, Folder 9)
  - Mathematics, physics and finance topics originating in fractal geometry (lightly edited draft) (Box 220, Folder 10)
  - A maverick's apprenticeship (clean drafts) (Box 220, Folder 11)
  - Mean devil functions, mean mass prefactors, and fractal lacunarity (heavily edited draft) (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Mean range of linearly dependent normal variables with application to storage problems: Comment and elaborations, circa 1979 (typescript/photocopy drafts, edited) (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Measures of fractal lacunarity: Minkowski content and alternatives (heavily edited drafts) (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Measures of lacunarity for some fractal dusts, BBM, J. Klenk, D. Fracchia (heavily edited computer printout drafts) (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - A mechanism of forecasting and a class of price 'patterns', 1964 (clean photocopy) (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Mergers, Levy's stable Paretian laws and related matters, circa 1960s (clean typescript and photocopy) (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - Meso-, uni-, and multifractal finance: foreword and update by the author, 2002 (edited drafts) (Box 119, Folder 9)
  - Mild vs. wild randomness: Focusing on risks that matter, BBM and N. N. Taleb, 2006 (edited printouts) (Box 119, Folder 10)
  - The Minkowski measure and multifractal anomalies in variant measures of parabolic dynamic systems, 1992 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 119, Folder 11)
  - The Minkowski measure and multifractal anomalies in variant measures of parabolic dynamic systems, 1992 (heavily edited computer printouts) (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - A modular multifractal measure, and its "anomalies" left-sided f(a), 1990 (edited printouts) (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Des monstres inventes par Giuseppe Peano a la description fractale de la nature, 1986 edits (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Multifractal and generalized self-affinity, 1990 (handwritten/computer printout drafts, heavily edited) (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Multifractal "anomalies" and mysterious power laws explained by a simple example (heavily edited drafts) (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Multifractal "anomalies" of latent negative f(a) and of virtual negative a, and the critical dimensions Dq, 1988 Dec 13 (clean photocopy) (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - The multifractal character of financial prices: The case of exchange rates, BBM, A. Fisher, L. Calvet, 1996-1997 (drafts, graphs/plots of data) (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Multifractal measures, circa 1987 (clean draft) (Box 120, Folder 8)
  - Multifractal measures, C. J. G. Evertsz and BBM (edited computer printouts) (Box 120, Folders 9-10)
  - Multifractal Measures (heavily edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Multifractal Measures, especially for the geophysicist (heavily edited drafts), circa 1988-1989 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Multifractal Measures for the geophysicist (edited computer printout drafts), circa 1987-1988 (Box 124, Folders 3-4)
  - Multifractal measures through a multiplicative cascade of functions, Coppens and Mandelbrot, 1997 (edited photocopies) (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - Multifractal noises, 1990 (heavily edited handwritten/computer printout drafts) (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Multifractal "paradoxes" of latent negative f(alpha) and of virtual negative a, and the critical dimension Dq, circa 1988-1989 (edited computer printout drafts) (Box 124, Folders 7-8)
  - Multifractal paradoxes: Negative latent f(alpha) and dimensions, and negative alpha holders, in a general Gibbs formalism (edited computer printout drafts), 1988 Mar (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Multifractal power law distributions and other "anomalies" explained by a simple example (heavily edited drafts) (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - Multifractal products of cylindrical pulses, Julien Barral and BBM - drafts, correspondnce, 2000-2001 (Box 125, Folders 1-2)
  - Multifractal products of cylindrical pulses, Julien Barral and BBM, 2001 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Multifractal products of harmonics of periodic functions, J. Barral, Coppens, BBM, 1998-2001 (edited computer printout drafts) (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - Multifractal products of pulses (heavily edited drafts) (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Multifractal products of random weights, J. Barral and BBM (heavily edited handwritten/typescript draft) (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Multifractal scenarios in political economy and history (handwritten and computer printout drafts, heavily edited) (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Multifractality of Deutschemark/US Dollar exchange rates, Large deviations and the distributions of price changes, A multifractal model of asset returns, A. Fisher, L. Calvet, BBM, 1996-1997 (drafts, correspondence, referee reports, data, graphs) (Box 125, Folders 8-9)
  - Multifractality of Deutschemark/US Dollar exchange rates, Large deviations and the distributions of price changes, A multifractal model of asset returns, A. Fisher, L. Calvet, BBM, 1996-1997 (drafts, correspondence, referee reports, data, graphs) (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Multifractality of the harmonic measure of DLA and extended self-similarity, BBM and C. J. G. Evertsz, circa 1990 (edited computer printouts, figures, correspondence with editors) (Box 126, Folders 2-3)
  - Multifractals step-by-step, BBM, M. Frame, R. Eichler-West (clean computer printout draft), 2007 Feb (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Multiperiodic multifractal martingale measures, Barral, Coppens, Mandelbrot, 2002 Jul - 2003 Mar (edited drafts) (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Multiplicative paths to the Wiener measure and pseudo fractional Brownian motions, BBM and J. Barral, 2006 Oct 13 (clean draft) (Box 126, Folder 6)